Guide to the William F. Millier papers,1941-1999.
Millier, William F. Papers, 1941-1999
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
William F. Millier papers, 1941-1999.
21-11-3610
William F. Millier
1.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Photographs, Research Materials, Newspapers, Reports.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The collection contains biographical materials, sabbatical materials, various papers, memos, photographs, project notes, and course materials including notes and lectures. There is also a plaque from the Alumni Association of the New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor Millier received his Bachelor of Science degree from Cornell's College of Agriculture in October 1945. He then served as District Agricultural Engineer in the Department of Agricultural Engineering. Recognizing the need for a graduate degree and the challenges of ventilating dairy barns, he became a Research Assistant, working with Professor Clesson Turner, and earned his Ph.D. degree in 1950. Their innovative work created a ventilation system that remains a seminal development in ventilation of structures for dairy and other animals. In 1998 his work was honored by a plaque presented by the American Society of Agricultural Engineers. The plaque was installed at the entrance of Riley-Robb Hall on the Cornell campus. During his career at the Department of Agricultural Engineering, he was appointed as Associate professor with tenure in July 1956, and Professor in July 1964. He was awarded the status of Professor Emeritus on October 1, 1986.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The collection contains biographical materials, sabbatical materials, various papers, memos, photographs, project notes, and course materials including notes and lectures. There is also a plaque from the Alumni Association of the New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Millier, William F.; Turner, Clesson.; American Society of Agricultural Engineers.; Cornell University.Dept. of Agricultural Engineering.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences.
Subjects:
Agricultural Engineering.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. William F. Millier papers
  - Sabbatical materials, Aug. 1, 1975-Feb. 1, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Kenneth Elston Case, William Richards, Adjuster, Feb. 10, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, memo from ALS Alumni Affairs, April 26, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - United States Dept. of Agriculture-War Board, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 4-H Lessons-WWII, Agricultural Engineering Project, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "How the Slot Was Slit", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Various papers, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "The Ventilation of Dairy Stables With Electric Fans", 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Rationed and Unrationed Farm Machinery and Equipment, January, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Sabbatical 1967-1968, Univ. of California at Riverside; photos, notebook, 1967-1968; unknown (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Farmer's Wartime Handbook of Available Building Materials and Their Uses, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Class Notebook-Agriculture class notes, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Class Notebook-Plant Physiology 233, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Class Notebook-Zoology I, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Research Summary-Mechanical harvesting and handling of Fruits and Vegetables; Hatch 453, NE 93, 1966-1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Agricultural Engineering 414, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Agricultural Engineering 414, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Color Slides, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Transparencies, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Photos-Farm Equipment, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Photos-Bean Sprayer, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Seed Coatings" paper, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Ag Engineering 312-Class Lectures and Transparencies, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Agricultural Engineering 312-Fall 1977, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Apple Harvest Transparencies and Prints, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Agricultural Engineering Course 2-Spring 1955, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Pictures from Norway, November 2, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Agricultural Engineering Course 31, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Agricultural Engineering Course 31, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "The Reduction of Post-Harvest Deteriorations of Mechanically Harvested Citrus", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "Silage Moves from Silo to Feed Bunk", 1953 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, Plans, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - News Articles, Radio Talks, Speakers, etc., [1950?] (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Articles on Apple Harvesting, 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Biographical Material--1967-1970, 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Material--1970-1978, 1970-1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Material--1967-1999, 1967-1999 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Heat and Ventilation Design-Data, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "The Paraplow", November 14, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Agricultural Engineering Idea Sheet--365, #73, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Silo Fires, 1979-1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Agricultrual Engineering-Extension Bulletins, 1984, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Cooperative Extension Memos, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Agricultural Engineering Facts, Jan. 1984-Jan. 1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Agricultural Engineers' Notebook, Feb. 1984-May 1985 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - NE Regional Agricultural Engineering Service-Microcomputer Software Catalog, Fall, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Placque-Alumni Association Certificate of Recognition, Presented to William F. Millier, n.d. (Box 3)